Dorothy C. Miller
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence and Subject Files, circa 1912-1992, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-8, OV 27; 7.2 linear ft.)
  - Cyril, circa 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - C, Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Cady, Sam -- Claflin, A., circa 1967-circa 1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Clara Diament Gallery -- Cole, Joyce, 1970-1982 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Copley, A. Phillip -- Craft, Douglas, 1947-1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Cramer, Gerald -- Cuyler, Mrs. Gordon, 1938-1979 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Danton, Edith (Miller's niece), 1947, 1970-1985 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Davis, Stuart, 1940-1989 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - DeFeo, Jay, 1961-1978 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - De Kooning, Willem, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Delineator Clippings, 1916-1921 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - D'Harnoncourt, Rene, Sarah and Anne Rishel, circa 1968-circa 1971 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Dia Art Foundation, circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Dickinson, Edwin, 1961-1978 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Dienes, Ben, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Diller, Burgoyne, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Domoto, Hisao, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Dubinsky, George, 1974, (includes original print) (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Dudley, Dorothy, 1969-1977 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - D, Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Dana, John Cotton -- Davis, Warren, 1958-1984 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Dawson, Maniere -- Dienes, Dr. Louis, 1959-1980 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Dieringer, E. -- Dwinger, Jonna, 1967-1976 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Eddy Family Association, 1966-1977 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Employment Requests and Recommendations, 1951-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Evans, Walker, 1968-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - E, Miscellaneous: Earnest, Adele -- Eversley, Fred, 1918-1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fairbanks, Polly, circa 1969-circa 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Farmanfarmaian, Monir, circa 1975-1982, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Federal Art Patronage Notes, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Feininger, Julia, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Feitelson, Lorser, and Helen Lunderberg, 1961-1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Feminism, 1974, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Field, Julie, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fiscbach Gallery, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fish, Janet, circa 1971-1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Fitzgerald, Astrid, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Flannagan, John, circa 1975 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Frankenstein, Alfred, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Fraudulent Art, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Friess, Constance, M. D., 1972-1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Fuller, Edmund L. (re: research on William Edmonson), 1968-1979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - F, Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Faison, S. L. -- Forakis, Peter, 1937-1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Forester, Russell -- Fuller, R. Buckminster, 1969-1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Galerie Espace NV, Netherlands, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Garreaud, Gaston, 1982-1985, (includes 4 ink sketches by Garreaud) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Godwin, Judith, 1976-1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Gorky, Arshile, 1942-1986, (see also Box 20, F 11-13) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Gourevitch, Jacqueline, 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Grandmother of Miller, circa 1930 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Graves, Bradford, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Graves, Morris, 1963-1982 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1972-1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - G, Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Gablik, Suzi -- Gomen, John, 1969-1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Good, Robert -- Guston, Philip, 1970-1980 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Hague, Raoul, 1964-1971 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Hartigan, Grace, 1957-1980, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 34-35)
  - Hatcher, Doris, circa 1960s-1975 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Herbst, Josephine, circa 1964-circa 1967 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Hiltunen, Eila, circa 1962-circa 1976 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Holt, Elizabeth, circa 1957-circa 1987, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 39-41)
  - Hood, Dorothy, circa 1972-circa 1981 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Horwitt, Will, 1970-1985, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 43-44)
  - H, Miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Haas, Elise -- Heller, Dorothy, circa 1966-circa 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Helmsley, Harry -- Hiss, Alger, circa 1969-circa 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Hitchcock, Henry-Russell -- Hogue, Alexander, circa 1961-circa 1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Hokanson, Hans -- Hurtubise, Jacques, circa 1967-circa 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Iceland, circa 1960s-circa 1970, (includes negatives and slides of Miller and others in Iceland) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Interests, circa 1930s-circa 1980s, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - International Council of the Museum of Modern Art, 1956-1988, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Isaacs, Julius, Will of, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - I, Miscellaneous, Indiana, Robert -- Israel, Margaret, circa 1963-circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Japanese Art, 1972-1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1964-1980, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
  - Johns, Jasper, 1965-1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Johnson, Anna (Holger Cahill's sister), 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Johnson, Floyd, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Johnson, Philip, circa 1960s-1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Johnson, Ray, 1966-1973 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    (includes mail art)
  - Josephson, Hannah and Matthew, circa 1961-circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Joslyn Art Museum, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Julien Levy Gallery: see Levy, Julien (Box 4)
  - J, Miscellaneous: Jaci Canning Enterprises -- Junior Council of the Museum of Modern Art, circa 1967-circa 1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Kawashima, Takeshi, circa 1972-circa 1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Keck, Caroline and Sheldon, circa 1961-circa 1983 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Klein, Basha: see Boris, Bessie (Box 4)
  - Knowlton, Grace, circa 1972-circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Kornblee, circa 1968-circa 1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Kruger, Louise, circa 1975-circa 1980 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - K, Miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Kahnweiler, Daniel-Henry -- Klavun, Betty, 1972-1983 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Kline, Franz -- Kusama, Yayoi, 1956-1980 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Lambie, Elizabeth Litchfield, circa 1952-1977 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Larrain, Emilio Rodriguez, 1975-1984 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Lekakis, Michael, circa 1960s-1978 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Levy, Julien, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Liebmann, Gerhardt, circa 1972-1977 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Lindley, Frances (Stronsky), circa 1950s-1987 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Livingstone, Biganess, circa 1969-circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Lundeberg, Helen: see Feitelson, Lorser (Box 4)
  - Lynes, Russell, circa 1970-circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - L, Miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Lamagna Gallery -- Lejwa, M., circa 1962-circa 1984 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Leonid, L. -- Lytle, R., 1956-1984 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - MacIver, Loren, 1939-1987, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Maine Articles, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Martin, Fred, circa 1960-circa 1973, (includes original artwork) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Matisse, Pierre, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Mayan Art, 1974, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - McAndrew, John and Betty (see also: Save Venice), circa 1961-circa 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Meadmore, Clement, 1968-1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1973-1981, (2 folders of clippings) (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Meyerhoff, Jane, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Miller, A. Barrett (Miller's brother), circa 1970-circa 1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Miller, Dorothy C., Early Correspondence, circa 1912-circa 1918 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Miller, Dorothy C., Letters from Smith College, circa 1921-1922, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
  - Miller, Dorothy C., Letters to Family, 1923-1925 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Moore, Henry, 1955, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston: see Buxton, Mary (Box 5)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Springfield, Massachusetts, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1960-1980, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
  - M, Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Mabry, Thomas -- Mangione, Jerre, circa 1959-1980 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Mantegna, Andrea -- Marlowe, Sylvia, circa 1962-circa 1981 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Maron, Jeffrey -- McSherry, Fred, 1959-1985 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Meiss, Millard -- Meyerowitz, Patricia, 1967-1980 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Michener, James A. -- Montclair Art Museum, 1965-1984 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Morgan, Elizabeth -- Mystic Seaport, Inc., 1966-1979 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Nantucket Articles, 1965-1977 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - National Gallery of Victoria, Australia, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - National Museum of Women's Art, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Naylor, J. Geoff, 1974-1978 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Nevelson, Louise, 1942-1990, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 32-34)
  - Newark Museum and Tours, 1928, circa 1957-1983 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Newman, Barnett, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Niizuma, Minoru, 1970-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Noguchi, Isamu, 1969-1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - North Carolina Museum of Art, circa 1950s-circa 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - N, Miscellaneous: Nagare, George -- Novros, David 1958-circa 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1945, 1970-1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Oldenburg, Claes, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Osborn, Robert and Elodie, circa 1964-circa 1982, (includes illustrated letters; 2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - O, Miscellaneous: O'Connor, Francis -- Ownby, Haynes 1950-1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Particular Passions: Talks with Women Who Have Shaped Our Times by Lynn Gilbert and Gaylen Moore (New York: Clarkson N. Potter-Crown, 1981), 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    (includes text of Miller's contribution)
  - Paule Anglim Associates, circa 1970-circa 1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Pei, I. M., 1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Picasso, Pablo, circa 1970s-circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Poetry, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Pollock, Jackson, 1967-1990 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - P, Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Paar, Sarah -- Penn, Arthur, circa 1965-circa 1982 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Pereira, Irene Rice -- Phoenix Gallery, 1948-1983, (includes artwork by Pereira) (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - PHP Institute -- Porter, Aline, 1969-1980 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Porter, Liliana -- Putnam, Wallace, 1968-1980 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Quaytman, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Reder, Ronnie, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Reichek, Jesse, 1967-1979 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Reineking, James, circa 1973-1976 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Reinhardt, Ad, 1959-1967 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Requests to Miller for Information, 1973-1978 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Rickey, George, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Rockwell, Norman, 1967, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Roerick, William, circa 1966-1978 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Rosenblum, Jay, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Rosevear, Cora 1969, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Rowan, Herman, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Rowlinson, Eric, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Russell, John, 1965-1976 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - R, Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Rabkin, Leo -- Rivers, Haywood Bill, 1961-1983 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Robus, Hugo -- Rutgers University, circa 1966-1985 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Sage, Kay (Tanguy) (research on), 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Sarah Lawrence College, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Save Venice (see also: McAndrew, John and Betty), 1970-1976 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Scharf, William, circa 1969-1985, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 41-42)
  - Schulte, Antoinette, 1965-1979 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Southeastern Center of Contemporary Arts (SECCA), 1975-1980, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 44-45)
  - Segal, George, 1971, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Seley, Jason, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Shahn, Ben, circa 1948, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Shaw, Charles, 1970-1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Sheeler, Charles, 1971-1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sihvonen, Oli and Clay Spohn, 1967-1977 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Simkovich, Helena, 1973-1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Sims, Patterson, circa 1972-1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, 1971-1983 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Smith, David, circa 1969-1976 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Smith, Margery, circa 1962-1981 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Smith, Susan, circa 1972-1975 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Soby, Jim, 1969-1979 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Soloman, Syd, circa 1973 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Spencer, Niles and Catherine Brett, circa 1939-1979 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Spohn, Clay: see Sihvonen, Oli and Clay Spohn (Box 7)
  - Stankiewicz, Richard, 1972-1980 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Stanton, Eleanor, circa 1965-circa 1975 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Steinberg, Saul, circa 1963-circa 1976 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Stella, Frank, 1976-1989 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Sterne, Hedda, 1962-1982, (includes 2 pencil sketches) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Sterne, Marietta, 1967-1980 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Stifler, Francis McIlhenny, 1956-1980 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Still, Clyfford, 1951-1986, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  - Stockbridge, Massachusetts, circa 1965-1985 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Sunami, Soichi, 1964-1976 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - S, Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Saarinen, Aline -- Schueler, Jon, 1957-1985 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Schultz, Antoinette -- Severni, Gino, 1962-1983 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Shapiro, David and Cecile -- SITE, Inc. (Sculpture in the Environmnent, Inc.), circa 1963-circa 1979 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Slaughter, C. D. -- Stark, Shirley, 1959-1982 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Steegmuller, Francis -- Sz, John, 1958-1982 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Taft, Edgar and Piri, circa 1959-1982 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Tajiri, Shinkichi, 1969-1974 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Tampa, Gasparilla Sidewalk Art Festival (1979), 1973-1979 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Tampa Museum of Art, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Tanglewood Lenox Massachusetts, Sculpture Exhibition, 1973-1977 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Theater, Music and Dance, 1959-1981 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Tippett, Bruce, 1972-1989 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Tobey, Mark, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Tomlin, Bradley Walker, circa 1954-circa 1976 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Travel, California, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Travel, California 1981 (Newark Museum Trip), 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Travel Correspondence, circa 1945-circa 1975, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 43-44)
  - Travel, Miscellaneous, circa 1956-circa 1983, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Travel, New Mexico, circa 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Travel to Tulsa, Philbrook Art Center, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Tworkov, Jack, circa 1967-circa 1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Tyler Graphico, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Typescript of Panel Discussion: The Club - "What Is the New Academy," 1959 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - T, Miscellaneous: Tavenner, Patricia -- Turturro, Domenick, circa 1958-circa 1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - U, Miscellaneous: Umlauf, Karl -- Union Theological Seminary, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified Surnames, 1956-1970 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Van Dalen, Anton, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - V, Miscellaneous: Vallila, Marja -- Vreeland, Frederick, circa 1958-circa 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - White, Alice Miller (Miller's sister), 1924, 1967-1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - White, Reid (Miller's nephew), circa 1964-circa 1984 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Whitechapel Art Gallery, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Williams, Hiram, 1966-1974 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Wilson, Eleanor (Siddy), circa 1963-circa 1983 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Wohl, Helmut and Alice, circa 1968-circa 1978 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Wolff, Robert J., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - W, Miscellaneous (Box 8)
    - Waddell, Chauncey -- Weber, Max, 1962-1980 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Wechter, Vivienne -- White, Robert, 1970-1980 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art -- Willard, Howard, 1965-1977 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Willard, Marian J. -- Wurzburger, Janet, circa 1964-circa 1984 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Y, Miscellaneous: Yaddo -- Young, Ruth, 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Z, Miscellaneous: Zabriskie Gallery -- Zeisler, Claire, 1969-1977 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Oversized Letters, Chryssa, 1961-1989, (Oversized letters from Chryssa from Box 2; 2 photos of the artist's studio and copies of 5 sketches of artwork) (Box 27 (OV))
- Rockefeller Family Art Collections, circa 1949-1985, Series 3:; (Boxes 8-12, 25; 3.9 linear ft.)
  This series documents Miller's consulting work with members of the Rockefeller family, primarily Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  3.1: Nelson A. Rockefeller, circa 1949-1985
  3.2: Other Rockefeller Family Members, 1956-1981
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller, circa 1949-1985, 3.1:
    Found here is signficant documentation of Miller's private curatorial and advisory work for Nelson Rockfeller, including the building his private collection and furnishing modern art work in public offices associated with Rockefeller. Also found here are files relating to the writing and publication of Miller's extensive catalog, Masterpieces of Modern Art, The Nelson A. Rockefeller Collection (New York: Hudson Hills Press, 1981.)
    There is general correspondence between Miller and Rockefeller concerning building the collection, often including Miller's handwritten notes, printed material related to artists and occasional photographs of artwork. Personal correspondence consists primarily of letters from Rockefeller to Miller thanking her for advice, assistance and gifts. Additional correspondence documents Miller's difficulties in securing payment for her years of work on the published catalog because Rockefeller died before the book was completed without having signed a formal contract with Miller.
    Additional files document federal government projects Miller completed for Rockefeller, including offering a selection of paintings to the Shah of Iran; a loan of artwork from the Museum of Modern Art to display in Secretary of State Henry Kissinger's State Department office; and providing artwork to furnish the nation's first official Vice-Presidential residence at the Admiral's House in Washington D.C. during Rockefeller's tenure as Vice President. Additionally, files document Miller's work with the Curatorial Committee for the Rockefeller collection at Kykuit and the family's home in Tarrytown, New York.
    There are files related to the 1969 exhibitions of Rockefeller collections at the Museum of Modern Art and the Museum of Primitive Art, and Rockefeller gifts to the Museum of Modern Art. Records relating to sculpture by Frederick Kiesler and tapestries by Joan Miró and Alexander Calder which Rockefeller considered for purchase are also included here.
    Most of the files in this subseries document Miller's work writing, compiling, and publishing The Nelson A. Rockefeller Collection: Masterpieces of Modern Art, which was based on the earlier catalog she wrote for the exhibition at the Museum of Modern Art in 1969. Records include correspondence, printed material, photos and photocopies of artwork, detailed information about individual works of art, meeting notes, drafts of the foreword and preface by Miller, and book copy text by John Russell, Alfred Barr, and Rockefeller. Additional files concern copy layout and illustrations for the book.
    - Correspondence, General, 1964-1972, (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 26-31)
    - Correspondence, General, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, General, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, General, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, General, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, Personal, circa 1949-1977, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 36-37)
    - Illustrated Art Lecture Transcript, New School for Social Research, New York, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Iranian Artists, circa 1970s (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Iranian Resort, Selections For, 1976, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
    - Kykuit, Pocantico Hills, Curatorial Committee, 1975-1978, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
    - Museum of Modern Art Exhibition (1969), and Gift to Museum, 1968-1976 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Museum of Primitive Art Exhibition (1969) and Gift to Museum of Modern Art, Printed Material, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Sculpture by Frederick Kiesler, 1967-1972 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Secretary of State Offices, 1973-1977, (6 folders) (Box 9, Folder 10-15)
    - Tapestries by Miró and Calder, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Vice Presidential Inaugural Medal Committee, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Vice Presidential Residence, 1975-1977, (8 folders) (Box 9, Folder 18-25)
    - Vice Presidential Residence, Photographs of Interior, circa 1976 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - News Clippings, 1962-1975 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - News Clippings, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - News Clippings, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 29-30)
    - News Clippings, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Collection Book (Box 9)
      - Acknowledgments and Introduction Drafts (by Rockefeller), 1978 (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Artwork Files A-C, circa 1950-circa 1978, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 33-34)
      - Artwork Files D-F, circa 1950-circa 1978, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 35-36)
      - Artwork Files G-J, circa 1950-circa 1978, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 37-38)
      - Artwork Files K-L, circa 1950-circa 1978, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 39-40)
      - Artwork Files M, circa 1950-circa 1978, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
      - Artwork Files N-P, circa 1950-circa 1978, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
      - Artwork Files R-S, circa 1950-circa 1978, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
      - Artwork Files T-Z, circa 1950-circa 1978 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Artwork, Photocopies of, circa 1979, (6 folders) (Box 10, Folder 8-13)
      - Artwork, Photographs of, circa 1963, (see also Box 25) (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Auction Catalog, Sotheby Park Bernet, Inc., Property of Nelson A. Rockefeller removed from his residences in Washington, D.C., New York, and Seal Harbor, Maine, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Catalog Cancellation Lists, circa 1971-1978, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
      - Catalog Draft, circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Catalog Draft, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Catalog Draft, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Catalog Draft, Working Copy 1, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Catalog Draft, Working Copy 2, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - Catalog Sheets, circa 1969, (6 folders; see also Artwork Files) (Box 10, Folder 23-28)
      - Catalog Sheets for 19th Century Artwork, 1977, (includes photos of artwork) (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence and Notes, 1969-1982, (5 folders) (Box 10, Folder 30-34)
      - Correspondence and Notes, 1969-1982, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
      - Correspondence, Copyright Issues, 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, John Russell, 1970-1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, Miller's Request for Payment, 1979-1985, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
      - Essay Drafts (by Barr), 1978 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Final Color Spread, Volume I, #1-47, 1979, (5 folders) (Box 11, Folder 9-13)
      - Final Color Spread, Volume II, #48-97, 1979, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 14-16)
      - Final Meeting on Book, 1979, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Foreword and Preface Draft by Miller, 1978-1981 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Invoices for Research Work on Book, 1971-1979 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Notes, circa 1978 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Notes, Layout of Book, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Notes, Questions about Artwork, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Notes, Research, circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Records of Acquisitions of Artwork Since 1970, 1970-1978 (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Records of Color Transparencies of Artwork in Rockefeller Collection, circa 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Records of Illustrations for Book, circa 1977-circa 1978, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 26-27)